# Juan José Martínez Medina

Guatemala (GMT-6) (+502) 40916176 iuanimm@amail.com

https://github.com/juanjmartinez https://www.linkedin.com/in/juanjomartinez

Software Developer

Software Developer with **10+ years of experience** developing web applications, applying the different stages from requirements analysis, design, development, testing and implementation. Experience using **React**, **React Native**, **JavaScript**, **HTML/CSS3**, **Angular**, **Typescript**, **Node JS**, **Java**, **C#**. Recognition in Ericsson for the proper implementation of the EIRG project form Millicom, making use of best development practices, agile scrum methodology and DevOps automation.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Runway Health, Full Stack Engineer — February 2022 - August 2022

Runway Health is a company focused on tele-medicine for travelers, they match travelers with US-licensed physicians prior to their travels ensuring they have the proper medication and support they need while they are away.

- Developed the functionality to medicate minors with parental consent.
- Implemented card data with stripe for user profile.
- Implemented Alerts in Slack with CircleCl and email notifications using webhooks.

Tech Stack: React, JavaScript, NodeJS, Typescript, Postgres.

#### Ericsson de Guatemala, IT Engineer/Tester— October 2018 - December 2021

Ericsson is a company with a portfolio of services focused on Networks, Digital Services, Managed Services and Emerging Business.

- Developed the EIRG project for Millicom in Panama, Costa Rica and Nicaragua, this project contributes to the management of recharge packages for telephone lines.
- Participated in the development of the IAP Platform for América Móvil, Mexico, this project allows the SIM's management for smart devices.

Tech Stack: React, JavaScript, Java with Spring Boot, Angular, Typescript.

## Banco Agromercantil, Programmer Analyst III — February 2010- December 2017

It provides different banking services to client's needs, such as loans, savings accounts, monetary accounts, debit and credit cards, promoting financial inclusion.

- Executed the migration project from Debit Card from Mastercard to Visa.
- Developed a system for alerts and exclusions for purchases abroad for Debit Card Module.

Tech Stack: .Net, Asp.Net, Visual Basic 6, SQL Server Business Intelligence, SQL Server, Sybase.

### **PROJECTS**

## **Ecommerce Site MiShop** – <u>www.mishop.gt</u>

Ecommerce Site dedicated to the sale of technology products, office, home and other categories.

 Developed the project for the ecommerce site MiShop.gt using React, JavaScript, Redux and Firebase, I integrated the VisaNet payment gateway.

## **SKILLS**

**Software Development**: Advanced: React, JavaScript, HTML5/CSS3. Intermediate: Angular, NodeJS, TypeScript, Java, C#. **Databases**: SQL Server, Oracle, Sybase, MySQL, Firebase.

**Tools:** .Net Core, Entity Framework, Springboot, Git/GitLab, Postman, Docker, Jira, Robot Framework, Selenium, Circle Cl. **Languages:** English, Intermediate; Spanish, Native.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Mariano Galvez University** – Guatemala, Guatemala  $3^{rd}$  year completed in the Systems Engineering Career - 2015.

National Institute of Bachelor's in computing – Guatemala, Guatemala

Bachelor's degree in computer with Science Orientation.